

ANTHONY CHIDI NNAMCHI

Software Developer

EXPERIENCE

Administrative/Software Manager LUMEN-DEO REALITIES AND CONSTRUCTIONS LTD

Abuja, FCT, NGN

September 2016 - Present

- Declined cost of management by 42% through labour reduction by the creation of electronic database systems through various spreadsheets, databases, and report files.
- Developed 25 personnel on the ability to succeed in adverse conditions through intensive training and shared knowledge.
- Provided of over 15 solutions that are user responsive and efficient using markup languages.
- Upgraded and maintained over 10 different codes.
- Formed 1 solution in collaboration with the back-end developers and web designers to improve usability.
- Set up and trained staff of 15 on the use of Microsoft Office programs.
- Part of the team that created workerbull.com, a UK based organisation, using WordPress
- Established websites using frontend tools like HTML, CSS, JavaScript and even React.js.
- Created and controlled code versions of over 15 solutions ever formed.

Administrative Officer/Software Engineer AVASTONE GLOBAL SERVICES LTD

Abuia, FCT, NGN

April 2016 - August 2016

- Slashed payroll/benefits and administration costs by 19% via negotiating pricing and fees, while ensuring the continuation and enhancements of services.
- Increased customer management, service and care by 21% utilizing personnel improved training on the use of Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint.
- Enjoyed a 97% satisfaction rating over a 4-week period as an administrative officer.
- Exploited my software engineering skill to manage the software installation and maintenance of 15 computer sets.

Station Manager

CEN-STRONG NIGERIA LTD

Omor, Anambra State, NGN September 2014 – March 2016

- Produced 15 proficient administrative staff via recruitment, selection, orientation, training and development.
- Introduced electronic reporting thereby slashing the time, power & error accruing from manual reporting by 62%.
- Formulated an extensive marketing plan that gave the leverage to exceed retail sales goals by an average of 13% every quarter in 2014 and 2015.
- Compressed cost of equipment maintenance by 17.7% via adequate management and maintenance policies.
- Grew core customers' list by 40% in 8 months without expanding the monthly budget.

+234 703 085 2400 nnamchianthony@yahoo.com https://naccyportfolio.herokuapp.com/

Abuja, FCT, Nigeria

SUMMARY

Have enjoyed over 11 years of overall work experience and a minimum of 5 years of technological experience. Have, as well, thrived in challenging organisations where information technology, human resource management, administration, sales and marketing, engineering, technical and cognitive skills have been maximized to meeting organisational goals.

SKILLS

Leadership	Advanced
Teamwork	Advanced
Problem Solving Skills	Advanced
Communication	Expert
Teaching Skills	Expert
Research & Analysis Skills	Advanced
Ability to Multitask	Advanced
Motivation	Expert
Management	Expert
Experience	Expert
Reporting	Advanced
Excellent writing	Expert

SOFTWARE SKILLS

HTML5	Expert
CSS3	Advanced
JavaScript	Advanced
React.js	Advanced
Nodejs	Advanced
PHP	Beginner
Python	Advanced
С	Advanced
jQuery	Advanced
Bootstrap	Expert
Git	Advanced
Github	Advanced
WordPress	Advanced
Canva	Advanced
Figma	Intermediate
Photoshop	Advanced
Corel Draw	Expert
Microsoft Office Suites	Advanced
EJS	Intermediate
Express.js	Advanced

LANGUAGES

English Native

Legal Secretary

CRIME VICTIMS FOUNDATION (CRIVIFON) LIMITED BY GUARANTEE

Abuja, FCT, NGN

April 2013 - November 2013

 Handled all secretarial duties including correspondence, reports and documents, coordination of meetings & conferences.

Laboratory Assistant

PYMOTECH RESEARCH CENTRE AND LABORATORY

Abakpa-Nike, Enugu, NGN

September 2009 - September 2010

- Optimised the workload on the laboratory attendants by 15% within 14 days at work
- Introduced the use of design expert software for data analysis thereby optimizing time factor.

ICT Officer

KRISINTEL COMPUTERS

Enugu, NGN

January 2006 - October 2007

- Trained fresh and returning students in the excess of 200 numbers on the basic concepts and principles of computer science.
- Introduced and led a team of 3 employees for regular training and development of all the staff for adequate customer service provision.
- Reduced the duration for the students training by 20% with increased students' productivity through regular observation and evaluation of students' performance.
- Developed more than 4 lesson plans, instructional materials and other strategies to ensure that every student has a thorough knowledge of the subject.
- Produced over 40 highly trained computer intellectuals through the introduction of regular student progress check.

EDUCATION

Harvard School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Cambridge, USA Professional Certificate Computer Science December 2022

Federal University of Technology, Minna September 2021 Master of Engineering Chemical Engineering

Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka September 2014 Bachelor of Engineering Chemical Engineering

Institute of Management and Technology, Enugu September 2010 Ordinary National Diploma. Chemical Engineering

CERTIFICATES

Certificate of Training Completion, Business Management TONY ELUMELU FOUNDATION July 2022

Certificate of Completion, Learn the Basics of Regular Expressions CODECADEMY December 2021

Certificate of Completion, Learn React Course CODECADEMY December 2021

Certificate of Completion, Google Africa Developer Training Program GOOGLE DEVELOPERS February 2021

Certificate of Completion, Frontend Web Development GENESYS TECH HUB February 2021

Certificate of Completion, Research Ethics Training Curriculum FHI360 December 2019

Certificate of Achievement on Energy Transition Innovation towards Low-Carbon Future IFP SCHOOLS May 2019

Certificate of Proficiency Human Resources and Skills Acquisition Programme HOREBSON RESOURCES April 2016

Bachelor of Engineering CHEMICAL ENGINEERING September 2014

Diploma in Engineering CHEMICAL ENGINEERING September 2010

Certificate of Proficiency in Computer Operation PACKAGE COMPUTERS

November 2005